<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>software on Samantha Robertson</title>
    <link>/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in software on Samantha Robertson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A SimVascular Plug-in</title>
      <link>/project/simvascular/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/simvascular/</guid>
      <description>Background
SimVascular is an open-source software project partly based in the Stanford Cardiovascular Biomechanics Computation Lab, where I spent the Summer of 2018 with support from the Stanford Bioengineering REU program. SimVascular enables segmentation of medical image data to develop 3-dimensional cardiovascular models, which can then be used for patient-specific simulation and analysis of bloodflow.
Overview
My summer project involved developing a GUI plug-in for the software that would allow researchers to rapidly prototype and run simulations on lumped parameter models of the cardiovascular system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LiCoRICE</title>
      <link>/project/licorice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/licorice/</guid>
      <description>LiCoRICE is an open-source, realtime computation platform specialized for systems neuroscience experimentation. It has been developed in the Brain Interfacing Lab is now the system used to run the group&amp;rsquo;s closed-loop brain interface experiments. The platform is written in C and Python, and is specifically designed with a modular architecture to allow easy prototyping of models by experimenters using only Python.
I joined the LiCoRICE project in the Summer of 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Open-Source Realtime Computation Platform</title>
      <link>/publication/licorice-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/licorice-one/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>