<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Samantha Robertson</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Samantha Robertson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Women in Parliament Worldwide</title>
      <link>/post/2019-08-07-womeninparliament/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-08-07-womeninparliament/</guid>
      <description>This week’s RWeekly digest included an awesome dataset from the World Bank that documents the percentage of women in lower house parliament across the globe from 1997 to 2018. The dataset is nearly complete and also includes summary statistics for numerous geographic aggregations.
All of my code to process and explore the data is available on my GitHub. There’s lots of interesting things to look at in this data, so I will leave most of the boring stuff out of this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much Do Australians Know About Their Parliament?</title>
      <link>/post/2019-04-29-auselectionpoll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-04-29-auselectionpoll/</guid>
      <description>It’s not often I see a cool data project focused on Australia, and in particular Australian politics, so I was especially excited to see freerangestats’ exploration of the 2016 Australian Election Study featured in RWeekly this week! The RWeekly email included this visualization, showing the responses to 6 questions about Australia’s parliamentary system, organized by party preference for Senate in the 2013 Federal Election.
At first, I was excited to see where voters for my party came in relative to other voters in parliamentary trivia, but then… how can I even compare?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#SWDChallenge March 2019</title>
      <link>/post/2019-03-07-swdchallenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-03-07-swdchallenge/</guid>
      <description>This month I decided to take part in the Storytelling With Data monthly challenge for the first time! The dataset we were given to explore contains global aid exchanges between 47 countries across the world across the years 1973-2013. The goal is to create visualizations that answers the broad question: Who Donates?, as well as some bonus questions about distribution of donations geographically, temporally and by purpose of donation. Here’s my initial attempt!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Course Descriptions</title>
      <link>/post/2019-02-28-visualizing-course-descriptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-02-28-visualizing-course-descriptions/</guid>
      <description>As my senior year at Stanford nears the end, I’ve started to think more and more about what I’ve really learned here, and what I’ll be taking away from my undergraduate experience. Sure, there’s plenty of sappy stuff about coming of age and figuring out what I want to start doing with my life (spoiler: haven’t figured it out), but what about concrete knowledge I’ve gained from my classes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>