<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data-science on Samantha Robertson</title>
    <link>/tags/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data-science on Samantha Robertson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Race, Wealth and Education in America</title>
      <link>/project/race-educ/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/race-educ/</guid>
      <description>Students in Data Challenge Lab, the data science intensive course taught by Bill Behrman and Hadley Wickham, pursue a quarter-long data exploration and analysis project of their choice using the Tidyverse R skills they learn in the course. My project explored the dataset released by the Stanford Education Data Archive along with the publication The Geography of Racial/Ethic Test Score Gaps, (Reardon, Kalogrides and Shores, 2017). Using a number of creative data visualization techniques, including some inspired by the New York Times interactive based on the paper, I was able to explore the education achievement gap between students of different races and with parents of different income and education levels geographically, by subject and by student age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stanford Open Policing Project</title>
      <link>/project/opp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/opp/</guid>
      <description>In the Fall of 2018, I worked with the researchers at the Stanford Open Policing Project (OPP) in the Stanford Computational Policy Lab, to implement and run the Veil of Darkness Test, as proposed by Grogger &amp;amp; Ridgeway in 2006 using the large OPP dataset. The premise of the test is that the race of a driver is less visible to the police when it is dark outside than when it is light.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>